[
    {
        "question": "............... in India is seen to be making conscious efforts to make political process transparent.",
        "options": [
            "Executive",
            "Legislature",
            "Judiciary",
            "Organisation"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "............... are made through interaction with the people.",
        "options": [
            "Public polices",
            "Programmes",
            "Project",
            "Public"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "............... began as a movement to remove injustice against aggressive landless farmers and tribal people.",
        "options": [
            "Terrorism",
            "Naxalism",
            "Measures",
            "Policies"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "India democracy faces other ............... challenges.",
        "options": [
            "Political",
            "Social",
            "Economic",
            "Different"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "To increase political participation of women ............... seats are kept reserved in local self governinginstitutions.",
        "options": [
            "33%",
            "27%",
            "50%",
            "25%"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "Corruption in the ............... process reduces people’s confidence in the democratic process.",
        "options": [
            "Electoral",
            "Political",
            "Social",
            "Democratic"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Everyone at social and ............... level should make conscious efforts towards it.",
        "options": [
            "Individual",
            "Political",
            "Economic",
            "Administrative"
        ],
        "answer":1
    },
    {
        "question": "Governments working capacity is reduced due to corruption at the political and ............... levels.",
        "options": [
            "Economic",
            "Social",
            "Administrative",
            "Confidence"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Nexalite movement the ............... of the problems of farmers and tribal people has reduced.",
        "options": [
            "Policies",
            "Tactus",
            "Importance",
            "Capacity"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "All religious, linguistic ethnic and caste groups should get ............... opportunity to participate in the decision making process.",
        "options": [
            "Justice",
            "Unequal",
            "Stable",
            "Equal"
        ],
        "answer":4 
    },
    {
        "question": "To prevent criminalisation of policies judiciary has adopted measures like strict ...............",
        "options": [
            "Punishment",
            "Fine",
            "Reward",
            "Discard"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "To make democracy more meaningful the government of India adopted the policy of ............... for women.",
        "options": [
            "Empowerment",
            "Rights",
            "Reservation",
            "Measures"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "............... and the resultant terrorism is one of the major challenges before Indian democracy",
        "options": [
            "Religious conflict",
            "Fight",
            "Dispute",
            "Injustice"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": ".............. opinion has a lot of importance in Democracy.",
        "options": [
            "Minority",
            "Marginal",
            "Majority",
            "Backward"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "Increased participation of ............... in political process is another serious problem for democratic systems.",
        "options": [
            "Politicians",
            "Criminals",
            "Candidature",
            "Public"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "People’s ............... is democratic process reduces to a great extent due to terrorism.",
        "options": [
            "Participation",
            "Help",
            "Support",
            "Fight"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "For the success of democracy everyone should keep in mind that we are …………… citizens of the nation.",
        "options": [
            "Responsible",
            "Proud",
            "Great",
            "Active"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "To make Indian democracy truly successful, it is essential to increase ............... of people at all levels.",
        "options": [
            "Workload",
            "Project",
            "Participation",
            "Change"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "Social ............... gets hampered due to increasing religious hostility",
        "options": [
            "Unstable",
            "Stability",
            "Conflict",
            "Forces"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Democracy aims at the ............... of majority of people.",
        "options": [
            "Welfare",
            "Development",
            "Wellbeing",
            "Opportunity"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    }
]